nmm.ac.uk 2019-06-26

# Privacy Notice | Royal Museums Greenwich | UNESCO World Heritage Site In London

For the purposes of the Data Protection Act, the Data Controller is the Board of Trustees of the National Maritime Museum.

### What personal information do we collect about you?

We collect personal information about you, such as your name and address and the details we require for payment, when you register with us, purchase tickets or place an order for products or services. We also collect information when you voluntarily complete customer surveys, provide feedback and participate in competitions. Website usage information is collected using cookies. 

### How will we use the information about you?

We collect information about you to process any orders, manage any accounts and, if you agree by giving us your consent, to contact you with updates about our latest news, events and offers which we think may be of interest to you. 

We will collect and process data where it is necessary to do so for our legitimate interests (for example we may collect and process data of supporters and potential supporters from publically available sources). We collect data for purposes of administration (to keep an up-to-date record of our relationships and administer donations), to further our charitable aims and to facilitate a supporter journey of the best possible standard.

If you have signed up to hear more from us, we may also use your information to improve the relevancy of our marketing communications. We will never share your information with third parties for their marketing purposes without your consent. We will never sell your information to third parties. 

### How will we protect your data?

We follow appropriate security procedures in the storage and disclosure of personal data so as to guard against loss, damage and unauthorised access by third parties and have robust technological solutions to ensure your personal data is protected from unauthorised access. We also require those external parties to whom we transfer personal data to comply with the same.

### Newsletter

We would like to send you information about our latest news, offers and events via our email newsletter, but we will only do this with your consent.

If you have signed up to our newsletter you can opt out at any time by clicking the ‘Unsubscribe’ link at the bottom of any newsletter. You can also ask to be deleted from our list at any time by contacting [rmgenquiries@rmg.co.uk](mailto:rmgenquiries@rmg.co.uk).

We use Mailchimp to send our email newsletter and Mailchimp securely store your personal data on our behalf. The entire Mailchimp application is encrypted to secure your personal data.

### Access to your information and its accuracy

You have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you. We want to make sure that your personal information is accurate and up to date so you may ask us to correct or remove information you think is inaccurate or unnecessary. 

You also have the right to request that your data is deleted.

If you would like a copy of your personal information, please email or write to us at the following address:

Christopher Gray, Museum Secretary

National Maritime Museum

Park Row

London, SE10 9NF

### Cookies

Cookies are text files placed on your computer to collect standard internet log information and visitor behaviour information. This information is used to track visitor use of the website and to compile statistical reports on website activity.

We use Google advertising cookies to:

  * Create Remarketing Audiences based on specific behavior, demographic, and interest data, and share those lists with Google Ads
  * Create Segments based on demographic and interest data

If your browser permits you can set your computer to reject cookies, although this may affect the quality of your visit. Depending on your web browser, you may also be able to block or delete specific cookies using browser tool settings. You can opt-out of Google Analytics Advertising Features through Ads Settings, Ad Settings for mobile apps, or any other available means (for example, the NAI's consumer opt-out). [Get more information on Google opt out options.](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/)

To find out more, read our cookie policy

### Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics to monitor how people use our websites and aggregate general statistics about customers, traffic patterns and related site information. It is always collected and analysed in an anonymous form. 

### Online donations

We have enabled online donations to be made to the Museum through a fundraising website provided by RaisingIT.

Financial transactions relating to our fundraising website may be handled by our payment services providers, Stripe and GoCardless. Royal Museums Greenwich will share transaction data with our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing your payments, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds.

For more information on Stripe's privacy policies and practices, [visit their website](http://stripe.com/gb/privacy).

For more information on GoCardless's privacy policies and practices, [visit their website](https://gocardless.com/legal/privacy/).

Your data may also be available to our website provider RaisingIT to enable them to deliver their service to Royal Museums Greenwich, carry out analysis and research on demographics, interests and behaviour of our users and supporters to help Royal Museums Greenwich gain a better understanding of them to enable RaisingIT to improve their services. This may include connecting data RaisingIT receive from you on the website to data available from other sources. Your personally identifiable data will only be used where it is necessary for the analysis required, and where your interests for privacy are not deemed to outweigh RaisingIT’s legitimate interests in developing new services for Royal Museums Greenwich. In the case of this activity the following will apply:

1\. Your data will be made available to our website provider RaisingIT

2\. The data that may be available to them to include any of the data we collect as described in this policy.

3\. Our website provider will not transfer your data to any other third party, or transfer your data outside of the EEA.

4\. This processing does not affect your rights as detailed in this privacy policy.

Your personal data will be stored and used by Royal Museums Greenwich in accordance with our privacy policy. We will only keep your personal information for as long as it is necessary for the purposes set out in our privacy policy and to fulfill the purposes for which the information was originally collected. 

### Booking tickets online

Our ticket booking system is provided by Gateway Galaxy. The booking system collects personal information on behalf of the Museum and enables us to process your transaction. We only use personal data where it is necessary to fulfil your order, communicate key information, products and services related to your ticket or visit and deliver customer support services. We will not disclose personal data to other parties. 

We will keep your personal information regarding such transactions as ticket purchases for a maximum of three years to enable follow up if required. 

If you make a booking and have opted into our email newsletter we may also use your information to improve the relevancy of our marketing communications.

### Using our online shop

Our Online Shop is provided by Shopify and Cybertill. Shopify and Cybertill collect information about you on our behalf in order to process any transactions and manage any accounts. We only use personal data where it is necessary to fulfil your order, communicate key information, products and services related to your transaction and deliver customer support services. Shopify and Cybertill use encryption to secure your personal data. 

Your personal information may be disclosed to other businesses within the Museums' partnerships and to reputable third parties who will help process your order. The National Maritime Museum requires all such third parties to treat your personal information as fully confidential and to fully comply with all applicable UK Data Protection and consumer legislation. We will not release your personal information to any company outside of the National Maritime Museum for mailing or marketing purposes.

If you agree by giving us your consent, we may contact you with updates about our latest news and offers which we think may be of interest to you. We may also use your information to improve the relevancy of our marketing communications. For more information see the Newsletter section above. 

### Membership

We will use your personal details to administer your Membership in accordance with the current Data Protection Act, General Data Protection Regulation, and as otherwise permitted or required by law. We will send Membership material by post such as your Membership welcome pack, Members’ magazines, What's On guides and Members’ Appeal information.

You will receive additional Membership information by email, such as e-newsletters, invitations to events, surveys and Members’ Appeal information if you have given your consent.

We will never pass on your personal details to other organisations. Your personal details are stored in the Gateway Galaxy database for the duration of your Membership and for 24 months after your Membership expires; after that we will dispose of your details securely

If you are a Member of the Flamsteed Astronomy Society, your email address will also be used by the Flamsteed Committee to communicate with you.

### Venue Hire and Corporate Events

We would like to send you information about industry news, upcoming events and venue highlights via our email newsletter, but we will only do this with your consent.

If you have signed up to our newsletter you can opt out at any time by clicking the ‘Unsubscribe’ link at the bottom of any newsletter. You can also ask to be deleted from our list at any time by contacting [events@rmg.co.uk](mailto:events@rmg.co.uk).

We use Mailchimp to send our email newsletter and Mailchimp securely store your personal data on our behalf. The entire Mailchimp application is encrypted to secure your personal data and we will never share your data with third parties for their marketing purposes.

### Social media

Our website uses the Facebook and Twitter share functionality on some pages.

### Other websites

Our website contains links to other websites. This privacy policy only applies to websites managed by the Museum, so if linking to other websites please refer to their privacy policies for further information. 

### Changes to our Privacy Notice

We keep our Privacy Notice under regular review and we will place any updates on this web page. This Privacy Notice was last updated on 07 January 2019.

**If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice please contact:**

Christopher Gray, Museum Secretary

National Maritime Museum

Park Row

London, SE10 9NF

For independent advice about data protection, privacy and data sharing issues, you can contact the Information Commissioner at: 

Wycliffe House, Water Lane

Wilmslow, Cheshire, SK9 5AF
